Alejandro Fernandez

Reset Specialist | Relief Sales Representative

Greetings, I am a highly motivated, agile and result-oriented individual with 8+ years of experience in the beverage industry. Experience that has led me to develop valuable skills of leadership and problem solving. Whether it be in my reset department helping maintain established business contracted relationships or having led a team of 20-25 frontline employees as a team lead in my merch department. I'm always with an eagerness to learn more as an individual and a collaborator.

afpato3@gmail.com



559-412-6938



Gustine, California



in linkedin.com/in/alejandro-fernandez-704730222

WORK EXPERIENCE

Reset Specialist | Relief Sales Representative Pepsi Bottling Group (PepsiCo)

11/2019 - Present Full-Time

Modesto, California

Tasks

- Primarily responsible for optimizing and resetting cold vaults and gondola space to PepsiCo merchandising standards. Executing chain specific planograms in smaller accounts like convenience and gas stores ranging all the way to small grocery stores.
- Utilized point of purchase in each account. Established positive working relationships with cross-functional contacts and primary contact at each account. All with minimal to no supervisor supervision.
- Relief Sales Representative Identifying customer sales opportunities. Selling and executing promotions, place equipment, and providing sufficient product volume to address the opportunities.
- Generating new selling opportunities by providing and maintaining excellent customer service to assigned accounts.

Merchandising Team Lead Pepsi Bottling Group (PepsiCo)

09/2017 - 10/2019

Modesto, California

Full-Time

Tasks

- Led a team of 20-25 frontline employees to merchandise accounts to key customers in a fast-paced direct store delivery environment.
- Briefed account merchandisers on scheduling and meeting key account goals.
- Anticipated potential customer issues; applied contingency planning to avoid customer dissatisfaction and communicated to the team to maintain customer satisfaction.
- All responsibilities above were taken care of while still executing and maintaining my key account route to PBNA merchandising standards.

Account Merchandiser

Pepsi Bottling Group (PepsiCo)

Modesto, California

Full-Time (03/2017 - 08/2017) | Part-Time (09/2014 - 02/2017)

Tacks

09/2014 - 08/2017

- Stocked and merchandised all points of purchase. Complied with account plano-grams by rotating shelved product, setting up displays, rotating coolers, storage room organization, and movement of product from storage to the sales floor.
- Responsible for maintaining key account assigned route to PBNA merchandising standards and customer account satisfaction with minimal to no supervisor supervision.
- Adapted and performed on a fast-paced direct store delivery environment.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Software Development Coding Dojo

09/2021 - 05/2022

Online

 Attended a highly immersive bootcamp learning full stack development from frontend and backend to database. Created and worked on projects from concept to finished materialization.

CERTIFICATES

Full Stack Software Development at Coding Dojo (09/2021 - 05/2022)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Personal Website & Portfolio (05/2022 - Present)

 Created my own personal portfolio website by using and implementing all the software tools that I learned at Coding Dojo's bootcamp.

LANGUAGES

Enalish

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Spanish

Native or Bilingual Proficiency